VEDANT SOLANKI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

PERSONAL PROFILE

SE II having 5+ years of experience in developing web and mobile applications specializing in Backend and API Development and super interested in learning Frontend Technologies. An inquisitive guy who loves Vi and Linux and who is interested in devising a simple and better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

SKILLS

• Languages : Python, JS, HTML / CSS

• Databases : MySQL, MongoDB

• Tools / Framework / Libraries : Django,

Git, Linux, React JS

WEBSITE

www.vedantsolanki.com

EDUCATION

B.E in Computer Engineering, May 2015 (Fr. Conceicao Rodrigues College of Engineering)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Photography
- Solo travelling
- Reading
- Sketching

CONTACT

Number: +91-8369367435 Email: lucifer.ved@gmail.com

Skype: ved.lucifer

linkedin:/in/vedantSolanki/

RECENT PROJECTS

Covid19 India Resources

 Built a web app to provide all covid1g related resources link at one single place. which includes filtering out oxygen, bed, medicines availability leads from Twitter and other government organisations.

Positive news web application

• Tried to solve real life problem of Mumbai local railway.

Memories - PhotoBlog

• Tried to solve real life problem of Mumbai local railway.

Blockchain Application

• Tried to solve real life problem of Mumbai local railway.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II

Visible Alpha, June 2017 - March 2021

- Designed and built a module used by hedge fund analysts to understand the deep forecast and historical data across multiple sectors and industries.
- Designed and built automated service to parse an XML file, scrape required data and feed it to the database.
- Co-Developed web analytics tool for a web application that logs user activity and provides detailed information about the activities performed by users on the entire application.
- Contributed to Sharding activity which improved data fetching performance of the entire application by 15 %
- Contributed in migrating entire application from Angular 2 to Angular 8

Python Django MySql PubSub Angular 8

Android Developer

Godcast Messenger, Feb 2016 - June 2017

 Co-Developed broadcast messaging app on android along with server side functionality and infrastructure requirement.

Android MongoDB Java Parse Server

Software Engineer Trainee

Vistaar Technologies , June 2015 - Feb 2016

 Participated in developing one of the module of pricing management solution for one of the Fortune 500 company.

Sencha Javascript